Harvard Graduate Student and Teaching Fellows Union Records TAM.077
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Harvard Graduate Student and Teaching Fellows Union Records
1967-1978
bulk
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Lasser, Carolyn
Harvard Graduate Student and Teaching Fellows Union
TAM.077
.75 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box and 1 half manuscript box.
The Harvard Graduate Students and Teaching Fellows Union was formed by 156 teaching fellows on March 13, 1972 in response to a change in the financial aid programs available to graduate students. The Union remained in existence through the 1972-1973 school year. This collection contains correspondence, membership lists, union statements, leaflets, newspaper clippings, posters and song lyrics.
Access Restrictions
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Tamiment Library & Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives for more information and to schedule an appointment, tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu or 212-998-2630.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Collection was acquired from Carolyn Lasser in 1978. The accession number associated with this collection is 1978.017.
Historical Note
The Harvard Graduate Students and Teaching Fellows Union was formed by 156 teaching fellows on March 13, 1972 in response to a change in the financial aid programs available to graduate students. The Union remained in existence through the 1972-1973 school year but no agreement was ever reached between the Union and the University.
Scope and Content Note
This collection contains correspondence, membership lists, union statements, leaflets, newspaper clippings, posters and song lyrics. There is also material from teaching assistant unions at other campuses. The collection covers the years 1967-1974, with the bulk of the material covering union activity from 1972-1973.
Arrangement
The materials in the collection were arranged alphabetically by subject.
Harvard University -- Professional staff.; Graduate teaching assistants -- Labor unions -- United States.; Graduate teaching assistants -- Labor unions -- Cambridge (Mass.); Songs (document genre); Correspondence.; Printed ephemera.; Clippings (information artifacts); Posters.; Harvard Graduate Student and Teaching Fellows Union; Lasser, Carolyn
- Accession Correspondence, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Constitution HGSTFU, Spring 1972-Summer 1972 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Contract HGSTFU; Proposed, Summer 1972 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, Mar 1972-Jun 1972 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Future of the Graduate School, Report of the Committee on, Mar 1969 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Hard Times, Apr 1972-Sep 1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Harvard Radical Union, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Leaflets and Songs, HGSTFU, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Lists, HGSTFU Committee Membership, Mar 1972 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Lists, HGSTFU Membership, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Lists, HGSTFU Picket Team, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- National Labor Relations Board, Apr 1972 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- News Articles, Mar 1972-Mar 1973 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Non-Harvard Union Materials, circa 1967-1972 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Non-Harvard Union Materials, circa late 1960s-early 1970s (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Non-Harvard Union Materials, 1968-1972 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Statements, Harvard Administration, Jan 1972-Jun 1973 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Statements, HGSTFU, Mar 1972-Spring 1973 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Status of Women in Faculty of Arts and Sciences, Report of the Committee on, Apr 1971 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Upstart, Apr 1972 (Box 2, Folder 7)